Javier Marin

Fulshear, TX 77441 | (832)748-7373 | jjmarin777@gmail.com GitHub | Portfolio | LinkedIn

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Junior Full Stack Developer with experience in frontend languages: JavaScript, HTML and CSS, as well as backend languages Java and Ruby. With 4 plus years of retail I possess strong skills in data analysis as well as team building that will help benefit my employers needs and further enhance my career goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React, Ruby, Rails, Java, HTML/CSS, SQL, AWS, Bootstrap, Spring boot, PostgreSQL, Git, Netlify, Node is, express, MongoDB

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

FureverHomes- Frontend Backend | Demo

Web application that helps users find nearby pets to adopt and or rehome a pet if needed.

- Fetched from an external API to get available pets.
- Implemented Authentication to have users logged in be persistent and keep track of user data.
- Used Google maps API to display nearby shelters.
- Applied bootstrap for styling.

Space Cowbov- Frontend | Backend | Demo

Retro style video game that users can play, create an account and keep track of their scores.

- Integrated Kaboom.js library to create game.
- Used React as frontend for user UI.
- Implemented Rails as my backend for data storage.
- Retrieved data using Axios.

Nutrition Calculator- Frontend Backend Demo

Web application that allows users to input nutritional information and keep track of their nutritional intake.

- Implemented React for my frontend UI.
- Styled with bootstrap to create visuals.
- Integrated SOLite for data storage.
- Used Active Record in Ruby to assist in data storage.

EXPERIENCE

Red Wing Shoe Co. Houston, TX Sales Associate 08/2017 - 10/2018

- Maintained organized presentable merchandise to drive continuous sales.
- Applied excellent communication skills and ability to establish rapport to close sales and meet targets.
- Worked along side retail representatives to boost sales by enhancing product presentations and advertising collateral.

Best Buy Co Inc. Houston, TX 05/2014 - 07/2016

Mobile Sales Consultant

- Used effective data analysis and sales strategies to increase profitability and develop systems or organizations for projects.
- Handled all aspects of the sale including: customer contracts and warranties, customer payments, cash and credit card/check transactions.
- Developed, maintained and communicated strong, up-to-date knowledge of wireless products, accessories, pricing plans and service features.

EDUCATION

University of Houston Houston, TX Bachelor of Science Computer Information Systems 05/2017 - 05/2022 Flatiron School Houston, TX Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 04/2021 - 07/2021 Lone Star College Houston, TX Associates of Arts 07/2013 - 08/2015